FLORENCE MBABAZI

mbabaziflorence07@gmail.com | +250782592552 | Kigali, Rwanda | https://github.com/mbabazif www.linkedin.com/in/florence-mbabazi | https://mbabazif.github.io/Portfolio/

Personal Statements

As a Data Analyst, I am passionate about developing Dashboards, Reports, Data Models, and performance-related insights. Since I can map the Business Requirements as a Business and Data Analyst and then translate them into operational dashboards and performance-related insights, I can always develop a solution without any miscommunication with stakeholders. Automating the processes concerning Data Extraction and Data Transformation also falls under my expertise.

Skills

Data Analyst

- Advanced Excel
- PowerBI
- SQL
- Python
- Machine Learning

Web Development

- Python(Django)
- HTMI
- CSS
- Bootstrap
- Postgres & Mysql

Personal Skills

- Continuous Learning
- Work under pressure
- Team Work
- Communication
- Accuracy and attention to details

Academic Qualification

AzubiAfrica(Acra, Ghana)

September 2022 - 2024

Business Analytics & Data Analytics

Award: Certificates

Skills:

- Data Cleaning
- Explore Important Formulas and Functions in MS Excel | Create Charts and Visualisations using MS Excel
- Load datasets and establish table relationships in PowerBI
- Build different types of charts and dashboards in PowerBI
- Work with Map visualizations and other advanced charts with drill-down functionalities in PowerBI
- Work with power query for data manipulation in PowerBI | Write DAX expressions in PowerBI
- Familiar with MySQL, Create & update reports in SQL | Perform Data Analysis using SQL
- Explore Python for Data Exploration and Statistical Inference
- Use Matplotlib and Seaborn for data visualization | Create charts to visualize data and generate insights
- Univariate, Bivariate, and Multivariate analysis using Python
- Perform Statistical Analysis on real-world datasets
- Build and Validate Hypothesis using statistical tests
- Generate useful insights from the data

Moringa School November 2018 - May 2019

Web Development Award: Certificate

Skills

Python(Django), HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, and Postgres

Inilak

May 2012 - December 2016

Bachelor Of Science in Information Systems and Management

Award: Bachelor's Degree

Skills:

 Networking, Information Security, Web programming, Management, Finance, Accounting, Cost Accounting, and Principle of Economics

Employment History

AzubiAfrica, Community Teaching Assistant and Scrum Master

Accra Ghana 2024 - Currently

Corhot 5 and Cohort 6

MobiCash LTD, Web Development, Kigali October 2019 - Currently Responsibilities:

- Integrating data from various back-end services and databases.
- Gathering and refining specifications and requirements based on technical needs.
- Creating and maintaining software documentation.
- We are designing website layouts and user interfaces using standard HTML, CSS, and JavaScript practices, along with the Django framework, Python, and other relevant tools.
- Maintaining, expanding, and scaling websites and web applications.
- Being responsible for the coding, design, and layout of a website according to the company's specifications.
- Familiarity with Operating Systems (Linux and Windows).

IT support officer Intern, Rwanda Education

Board, March 2017 - 2017

Responsibilities:

- Generating reports for each school to assist One Laptop Per Child in assessing the completion of the work.
- Installing and configuring computer hardware, operating systems, and required applications.
- As a help desk technician, I accomplish my tasks by listening to end users and acting on their feedback.
- Troubleshooting systems and network problems, such as checking the wireless adapter, WAN, and LAN connections, and verifying the wireless access point and network.
- Installing the Prodigy program on XO laptops to enable teachers and students to access content on the server using XO laptops.
- Maintaining the XO laptops and installing the key, as it expires after one year.
- Creating reports for each school to assist One Laptop Per Child in assessing the progress of the work.

Projects

Indian Startup Funding Ecosystem

• Indian startup ecosystem The analysis aims to uncover trends, patterns, and key factors that contribute to the success of startups in India. It's a data-cleaning project

Customer Churn Analysis and Prediction

Customer churn or turnover we aim to predict customer churn and understand the key indicators of churn by analyzing a dataset containing various customer attributes. It's a machine-learning project

Corporation Favorita Sales Prediction

 Corporation Favorita is a large Ecuadorian-based grocery retailer. This project involves predicting future sales for a grocery retailer based on historical sales data and other relevant information.

Sepsis Analysis(FastAPI)

• This project focuses on early sepsis detection and classification, a critical aspect of healthcare. Timely identification of sepsis significantly enhances patient outcomes.

References

Jackeline Kayitesi System Administrator ISCO Rwanda Ltd Tel: +250788312907

Email: kayitesijacqueline@gmail.com

Alexianne Imanirakarama Web Developer Phone: +250783351129 Email: imalexianne@gmail.com Tuyisenge Marie Claire Technical Support Engineer Tek Experts Phone: +250784357668

Phone: +250/8435/668 Email: tblaguese1@gmail.com

Language

English(Excellent), Swahili(Good), Kinyarwanda(Excellent)